

(https://epd.sutd.edu.sg)

(http://www.sutd.edu.sg)

HOME (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/) ABOUT > PEOPLE > EDUCATION > RESEARCH > RESOURCES > CAREERS (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/careers/) CONTACT US (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/contact-us/) Q

Faculty

- > Franklin Anariba (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/people /faculty/franklin-anariba)
- > Ang Lay Kee, Ricky (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/people /faculty/ang-lay-kee-ricky)
- > Avinash Baii (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg /people/faculty/avinash-baji)
- > Luciënne T.M. Blessing (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/people /faculty/lucienne-blessing)
- > Bong Eng Ying (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/people /faculty/bong-eng-ying)
- Roland Bouffanais (https://epd.sutd.edu.sg/people

# Michinao Hashimoto

### Assistant Professor

Email: hashimoto@sutd.edu.sg (mailto:hashimoto@sutd.edu.sg) Telephone: +65 6499 4867

Research Areas: Bio-Medical Engineering

Pillar / Cluster: Engineering Product Development

#### Biography

 $Dr.\ Michinao\ Hashimoto\ received\ B.S.\ degrees\ in\ Chemistry\ and\ Biochemistry/Biophysics\ with\ honors\ from\ Oregon\ State\ University\ in\ 2003,\ and\ Ph.D.\ degree\ from\ Harvard\ Ph.D.\ degree\ from\ Ph.D.\ deg$ University in 2009 under the guidance of Prof. George Whitesides. Prior to joining SUTD, he completed his postdoctoral training at MIT and Children's Hospital Boston under the profit of the prior ofthe guidance of Prof. Daniel Kohane and Prof. Robert Langer.

He has served as visiting scholars at multiple institutions, including Polish Academy of Science (Poland), University of Sao Paulo (Brazil), National Tsinghua University (Taiwan), the University of Tokyo (Japan), and Saudi Aramco (Saudi Arabia).

#### **Professional Appointments**

- 2014-present Assistant Professor, Singapore University of Technology and Design
   2009-2013 Postdoctoral Associate, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
   2009-2013 Postdoctoral Associate, Boston Children's Hospital
- 2004-2009 Graduate Research Assistant, Harvard University

### Education

PhD Chemical Physics, Harvard University, 2009
A.M. Chemistry, Harvard University, 2005

(http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200902164)

- B.S. (Honors) Chemistry, Oregon State University, 2003
- . B.S. (Honors) Biochemistry and Biophysics, Oregon State University, 2003

# Research Interest

Dr. Hashimoto's overarching research theme is microfluidics, both fundamentals and applications. Ongoing research topics include multiphase microfluidics, biomaterials formation, drug delivery, and development of medical and diagnostic devices. He is also interested in reducing the cost of science and technology, and making them accessible to broader range of people. Along this line, his research interest is on low-cost device fabrication and their application in point-of-care setting

# Selected Publication

- M. Hashimoto, R. Tong, D. S. Kohane, "Microdevices for Nanomedicine," Mol. Pharmaceutics, 2013, 10(6), 2127-44. http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/mp300652m M. Hashimoto, R. Langer, D. S. Kohane, "Benchtop fabrication of microfluidic systems based on curable polymers with improved solvent compatibility," Lab Chip, 2013,
- 13(2), 252-259. http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2lc40888k (http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2lc40888k)

  W. Choi, M. Hashimoto, A. K. Ellerbee, X. Chen, K. J. M. Bishop, P. Garstecki, H. A. Stone, and G. M. Whitesides, "Bubbles Navigating through Networks of Microchannels," Lab Chip, 2011, 11(23), 3970-8. http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c1lc20444k (http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c1lc20444k)
- M. Kubo, X. Li, C. Kim, M. Hashimoto, B. J. Wiley, D. Ham, G. M. Whitesides, "Stretchable Microfluidic Radio Frequency Antenna," Adv. Mater., 2010, 22(25), 2749-52. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/adma.200904201 (http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/adma.200904201)
   M. Hashimoto, G. M. Whitesides, "Formation of Bubbles in a Multi-section Flow-focusing Junction," Small, 2010, 6(9), 1051-9. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200902164
- M. Hashimoto, J. Feng, R. L. York, A. K. Ellerbee, G. Morrison, S. Thomas, L. Mahadevan, G. M. Whitesides, "Infochemistry: Encoding Information as Optical Pulses using Droplets in a Microfluidic Device," J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2009, 131(34), 12420–9. http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ja904788m (http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ja904788m)

  Q. Xu+, M. Hashimoto+, T. T. Dang, T. Hoare, D. S. Kohane, G. M. Whitesides, R. S. Langer and D. G. Anderson, "Preparation of Monodisperse Drug-loaded Polymer Microparticles Using a Microfluidic Flow-focusing Device, Small, 2009, 5, 1575-81. (+ equally contributed authors) http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200801855 (http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200801855)

  M. Hashimoto, S. S. Shevkoplyas, B. Zasońska, T. Szymborski, P. Garstecki, G. M. Whitesides, "Formation of Bubbles and Droplets in Parallel, Coupled Flow-focusing
- Geometries, Small, 2008, 4, 1795-1805. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200800591)

  M. Hashimoto, P. Garstecki, H. A. Stone, G. M. Whitesides, "Interfacial Instabilities in a Microfluidic Hele-Shaw Cell," Soft Matter, 2008, 4, 1403-13. http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/B715867J (http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/B715867J)
- M. Hashimoto, P. Garstecki, G. M. Whitesides, "Synthesis of Composite Emulsions and Complex Foams with the use of Microfluidic Flow-Focusing Devices," Small, 2007,
- 3(10), 1792-1802. http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200700238 (http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200700238)

   M. Hashimoto, B. Mayers, P. Garstecki, G. M. Whitesides, "Flowing Lattices of Bubbles as Tunable, Self-assembled Diffraction Gratings," Small, 2006, 2(11), 1292-98.
- http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200600211 (http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smll.200600211)

• M. Kubo, X. Li, C. Kim, M. Hashimoto, B. Wiley, D. Ham, and G. Whitesides. "Robust Stretchable Electronics," US Patent Application, filed 2010

- Bosch Fellowship for EuroScience Open Forum, Bosch Foundation, 2010
   60th Lindau Nobel Laureate Meetings, Japan Society of Promotion of Sciences, 2010
- Fieser Lecture Award, Department of Chemistry and Chemical Biology, Harvard University, 2008
   Nanoscale Science and Engineering Center Travel Fellowship, Harvard University, 2006
   Chemical Physics Student Fellowship, Harvard University, 2005
- . CUE Award, Distinction in Teaching, Harvard University, 2004

1 of 2 9/5/17, 10:02 AM



2 of 2